ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
煮粥达人
showeryhe
翻译
某羽
滚成一个团子
翻译
冬麟
潇湘月影
翻译
小酸奶!
时间轴
Kallen   youliss   仓鼠
特效
宝宝  草草
电脑狂人
第二季
第八集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
乔告诉我他们不怀好意  要糟蹋穆特尼
Joe told me they were gonna mess with it, with Mutiny.
-这回你倒相信他了  -对  我信
- And now you decide to believe him? - Yeah, I do.
他说的是实话  我看得出来
He was telling the truth. I could tell.
我就是看得出来
I just could.
-怎么  你生气了吗  -太对了
- What, are you mad? - Yeah, I am.
我想卖掉公司  顺便告诉你不止我这么想
I wanted to sell. And I'm not the only one, by the way.
但你完全忽视了我们的意见
But you completely disregarded that
就因为你能和他有什么神秘感应
based on some mysterious feeling you got off
而你还明明告诉我们不要相信他
the one person you told the rest of us never to trust.
我是不会道歉的
I'm not going to apologize.
你有意见吗
Is that going to be a problem?
没有
No.
等有了机会  我觉得我们得换一家网络
When we're able, I think we should find another network.
我们也该和乔·麦克米伦分道扬镳了
It's about time we got out of the Joe Macmillan business.
同意
Yeah, agreed.
-什么时候  -今早去市政厅办的
- When? - This morning at city hall.
我们希望你第一个知道
We wanted to tell you first.
你怎么能这么做
Why would you do that?
难道这种事不该事先告诉我一声吗
Don't you think that's something I'd wanna know about?
-不该让我在场吗  -我们希望就两个人
- To be there? - Well, we wanted it to be the two of us.
不要什么盛大婚宴  只有两个相爱的人
No big party, just two people in love.
别生气  爸  这是好事
Don't be upset, dad. This is good news.
我为你高兴
I'm happy for you.
不过就是  你是我的女儿
It's just... You're my daughter.
乔  我想你应该能明白
Joe, I'm sure you can understand
我为什么希望出席我唯一女儿的婚礼
why I'd want to be at my only daughter's wedding.
先生  我们绝不是有意不敬
Sir, we meant no disrespect.
你似乎特别喜欢对别人搞突然袭击
You seem to be making a habit of springing things on people.
这是我们共同的决定  又不是他逼我的
We did this together. It wasn't inflicted on me.
其实还是我拍板的呢
It was my decision, actually.
你为什么要觉得是在气你
Look, why are you making this about you?
我刚刚告诉你我结婚了
I just told you I got married.
你应该为我感到高兴
You should be happy for me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
你们俩新婚快乐
To both of you.
多谢
Thank you.
如果没什么事的话  我要去告诉卡罗琳了
Well, if you'll excuse me for a moment, I'll go tell Caroline.
也许她的态度会好些
Maybe I'll get a better reaction out of her.
你来不是光想说这一件事的吧
I take it there's something else you want to discuss with me?
莎拉很不喜欢卡罗琳
Sara can't stand Caroline.
虽然我非常感激您在这里给我的机会
As much as I appreciate the opportunity you've given me here,
但我想我该开始新的生活了
I think it's time for me to move on.
莎拉和我要搬去加州
Sara and I are moving to California.
抱歉同时把这么多意外丢给您
I'm sorry to lay all this on you at once.
不不  你说得对
No, no, no. You're right.
也许你是该向前看了
Maybe it is time to move on.
我没意见
No hard feelings.
祝你将来顺风顺水
Best of luck in all your future endeavors.
我很乐意帮你找一位继任者
Uh, I'm happy to help you find a replacement.
不用了  让我们的人来办就好
No, that's okay. I'll leave that up to our people.
-他们会找到合适人选的  -好
- They'll find the right guy. - Okay.
我可以多待一阵子  等你找到人再走
I can stick around until you've got someone in place.
说什么傻话
Don't be silly.
我连个像样的婚礼都不能给我女儿
I couldn't give my daughter a wedding.
最起码也要让她过个舒心蜜月吧
The least I can do is give her a honeymoon.
这么着
I'll tell you what.
你去找卡罗琳要我私人车库的钥匙
Ask Caroline for the keys to my private garage.
里面有辆57款的雪佛兰敞篷
There's a '57 bel air convertible in there,
崭新的  随开随走
pristine and ready to go.
你拿去开几周  出去好好逛逛
Take it for a couple of weeks. Hit the road.
我会和莎拉说一下的
Uh, I'll talk to Sara about that.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You bet.
我  很遗憾穆特尼的交易没成
I, uh... sorry the Mutiny deal didn't go through.
我在这行已经混了很久了
I've been in this game long enough
知道事情并不总会如我所愿
to know things don't always break my way.
蜜月愉快
Enjoy the honeymoon.
你好  戈登
Hey, Gordon.
怎么回事
What the heck?
抱歉
Sorry.
你没事吧  怎么了
You okay? What was it?
没什么
It was nothing.
欢迎穆特尼用户
好  我们调试了楼梯那段
Okay, we did the debugging of the staircase...
你重新配置了游戏菜单吗
and you reconfigured the game menu?
对  我想简单过一遍
Yeah, I want to go over it briefly,
但我觉得我们基本调试好了
But, yeah, I think we're basically there.
我们调试好了
We are there.
我们做到了  搞定了
We did it. It's done.
-完美了  -不  不
- It's perfect. - No. No.
我想再优化一些东西
I want to tweak a few more things
加上版权保护  或许
and copy protect it and maybe
重写屏幕顶上的滚动条信息
rewrite some of the scroll at the top.
-太乱了  -什么  版权保护吗
- It's messy. - What? Copy protect it?
但我们不那样  我们是穆特尼
But we don't do that. We're Mutiny.
我们都写了一些很棒的代码
Uh, well, we both wrote some pretty bitching code.
你希望被别人偷走吗
You want someone taking that?
我就是通过模仿再拆分别人的工作学的写代码
I learned to code by copying other people's work, pulling it apart.
你也一样
So did you.
对  我的工作也被剽窃过  并不美好
Yeah, I've also had my work stolen. It's not pretty.
如果你版权保护了视差  我们就不会相遇
We never would've met if you had copy protected "Parallax".
对  但我们相遇了
Yeah, but we did meet.
所以  鉴于我们已经相遇了
So, because we met,
现在我可以版权保护我们的工作
now I can copy protect our work
而不用担心我们不会相遇
without fear of us not meeting.
别这样  我们写了这么赞的游戏
Come on, we wrote this amazing game.
我不想被人从我们手中抢走
I don't want anyone taking it from us.
卡梅伦  你来不来
Hey, Cameron, you coming or what?
好了  都收拾好了
All right, yeah, everything's squared away.
酒桶已经送到  桌子也到了
Okay, kegs have been delivered, tables are here,
笨蛋在后面装广播系统呢
nitwit's setting up the PA out back.
你要带人来吗
You bringing anybody?
也许吧  到时候看
Maybe. We'll see.
会很有趣的
This is gonna be so much fun.
就像一次进行一百场奇怪的初次约会
Ugh, it's gonna be like a hundred awkward first dates at once.
天呐  这些人是谁  我们都不认识
God, who are these people? We don't even know.
这是友好地表示感谢他们
It's a nice way to say thank you
无论起落都坚持做我们的用户
for sticking with us through all the ups and downs.
这就要说到下一件事了
Which brings us to our next topic.
我们做得很棒
Uh, we're doing great.
社区日进斗金
Community's raking it in.
我们有越来越多的用户停留得越来越久
Hell, we got more and more users staying on for longer.
游戏呢
Uh, and games?
增长没那么快  但用户很忠实
Well, they're not growing as fast, but those users are loyal.
那些男孩不会去别的地方
Those boys ain't goin' anywhere.
我们有钱换网络吗
Can we afford to switch networks yet?
还不行  差不多了
Uh, not quite. Almost.
再多几周像上两周那样  我们就可以了
A few more weeks like the last couple, we'll get there.
好的
Okay.
就这样
Uh, that's it.
好
Great.
今天有15笔订单
15 orders today.
-嗯  -我去开
- Yeah. - I got it.
那是多少台
How many is that?
上次我数是250个
Around 250 last I counted.
-250 -是的
- 250? - Yeah.
我在一些高端生活杂志上登了广告
I took out some ads in some high-end lifestyle magazines.
我就跟那些笨蛋说他们该多留一阵
I told those dillweeds they'd wanna stick around.
只剩我们两个了  怎么赶得上进度
How are we supposed to keep up with that with only two of us left?
我们再招人
Well, we'll hire some more people.
公司正在蓬勃发展
Company thriving like this,
可以再招些有才华的年轻人
we can afford some young talent.
-那是什么  -退货
- What's that? - It's a return.
串行端口没有装对
The serial port wasn't installed correctly.
不会吧  拜托  这个谁做的
No way. Come on, guys. Who did this one?
克拉克电脑
戈登·克拉克
看这是谁呀
Look who I found.
-大坏蛋斯坦  -好啊  伙计们
- Big, bad Stan! - Howdy, fellas.
-你来这儿做什么  -回来一阵了
- What are you doing here? - Oh, back in town for a bit.
想来看看你们
Thought I'd stop by, see how you guys are doing.
西部那边怎么样  你在忙什么
How's everything going out west? What are you working on?
东弄弄西搞搞  很多事
Oh, this and that. A few things.
都在初期阶段
Just sort of germinatin'.
很爽  有很多风投注资
It's great. There's more VC money flyin' around
钱多得不知道怎么用了
than anyone knows what to do with.
-这边怎么样呢  -很好啊
- How's it going here? - Oh, great.
一切顺利  出乎意料得好
Going really great, you know? A little too great.
除非你想拿螺丝刀来帮忙
So unless you wanna pick up a screwdriver and pitch in,
我们就去干活儿了
we got work we've gotta do.
好吧  我过会儿应该会去"着陆"
Okay, well, I'll probably head over to the Landing in a little bit
你们可以找我一起吃午饭
if you guys want to meet up for lunch.
-当然  -听起来不错
- Yeah. Sure thing. - Sounds good.
他来了  乔  这是杰西·埃文斯
Ah, here he is. Joe, this is Jesse Evans.
欢迎  认识你很高兴
Oh, welcome. It's great to meet you.
我也是
You, too, man. You, too.
能来这里我很激动
Really excited to be here.
-路上如何  -很好  谢谢
- How was the trip? - Wonderful, thank you.
我们去西部度蜜月了  算是探探情况吧
Went on our honeymoon out west, sort of scouting it out.
乔就要带着我女儿逃去加利福利亚了
Joe is absconding with my daughter to California.
是打算开家自己的公司  和一些风投公司谈过
Um, started my own thing, talked to a few VC firms.
那不错啊  我才从那边过来
That's fantastic. I'm just coming from there.
你知道马克·默利斯吗
You know Mark Merlis?
嗯  以前在IBM时打过交道
Yeah, go back to my IBM days.
找他没错  人脉很广
Great guy to talk to. Knows everybody.
他安排我见了鲍伯·里德和斯图尔特·伍兹
He put me in touch with Bob Reed and Stuart Woods.
好巧  我跟他们一起打篮球
Amazing. They're in my pickup basketball game.
我搬来了这里  你以后可得替代我了
You'll have to sub in for me now that I'm here.
你认识杰夫·亚彻吗  我回头给你他的联系方式
You know Jeff Archer? I'll get you his info.
这家伙特别棒  相当聪明
Great guy, super smart.
你在那边做什么
What were you doing out there?
我创立了一家在线服务公司  系网
I started an online service, Symnet.
做得挺好  后来被甲骨文收购了
Did pretty well. Eventually got bought out by Oracle.
我拿那笔钱做了几项风投
Turned that money into a few different ventures.
两项在西部  一项在东京
A couple out west, one in Tokyo.
你也清楚这行怎么回事
You know how this business is.
总要四面撒网
Always gotta be moving in every direction.
当然
Yeah, sure do.
我很欣赏你在这边做的东西
Really love what you got going on here, though.
你发掘了相当好的机会
It's a fantastic opportunity you spotted.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
我一位好友做的硬件工作  戈登·克拉克
A good friend of mine did the hardware work, Gordon Clark.
他待会儿会过来带着你过一遍
He's coming by later to walk you through it.
很好
Great.
这方面我需要一切帮助
Use all the help I can get in that department.
杰西是负责把握大局的人
Jesse's more of a big picture guy.
那在你看来大局是什么样的呢
So, what is the big picture as you see it?
第一季度  我们可以进入4座城市
In q1, we could be in four cities--
达拉斯  纽约  旧金山  伦敦
Dallas, New york, San Francisco, and London.
到第四季度  可以发展到24座
By q4, we could be in 24.
像我们这样  在全球有分支
Positioned around the globe as we are,
具有如此规模  我们可以立刻
a company this size, we can arrive on the scene
以大人物的姿态出现
a major player right away.
不像刚起步的小公司那么不稳定
None of the uncertainty of a fledgling outfit.
喂
Hello?
茱尔丝
Jules?
好啊  怎么了
Oh, hey. What's up?
-午饭吃得怎么样  -挺好
- How was lunch? - Good, good.
-我们给你带了三明治  -谢谢
- We brought you a sandwich. - Oh, thanks. Thanks.
戈登  我们最近考虑了很多  我觉得...
Uh, Gordon, we've been giving it some thought, and, um, I think--
不是我们不相信你的公司
It's-- it's not that we don't believe in what you're doing here.
不  绝对不是
No, no. Heck, no.
但我们需要风险小点的工作
But we just need something a little less risky.
需要
Need something?
怎么  你们要辞职吗
What, you're quitting?
有什么风险呢  我们有250张订单要完成
What's the risk? We got 250 orders waiting to be filled.
是的  但我们太老了
We sure do, but we're a little old
不能把未来赌在这上面
to be bettin' our future on this.
怎么  斯坦带你们出去了一趟
So, what? Stan take you out,
在你们脑袋里灌满了
fill your head with visions
风投资金满地流的幻觉吗
of vc money flowing through the streets?
不  不是那样
Oh, no, that's not it at all.
那些厉害的硅谷公司
You know, these fancy silicon valley companies
也是从头起步的
started out somewhere,
而且绝不是在大公司的办公室里
and it's not in a big corporate office.
而是在一个车库里  三个人卷起袖子
It's in a garage with three guys rolling up their sleeves,
相信自己的能力  做出了伟大的东西
betting on themselves and making something great.
拜托  我们在共同奋斗
Come on, we are in this together.
好吧  没关系  没关系
You know what? It's fine. It's fine.
你们将来就是在外面看着羡慕的人
You know, you guys are gonna be the ones on the outside lookin' in.
我相信你说得对  但目前...
I'm sure you're right. But right now I--
我觉得我们已经拿定主意了
I think we've pretty much made up our minds.
你要接电话吗
You gonna answer that?
-喂  -茱尔丝是谁
- Hello? - Who's Jules?
-什么  -我刚刚打过一通电话
- What? - I called a second ago.
好像信号不好
I think the connection was bad.
没谁  你有什么事
Oh, uh, no one. What do you want?
你半小时前就该来西方集团了
You were supposed to be at Westgroup half an hour ago.
对  我...忘记了
Oh, yeah. I-- I forgot.
我马上过去
I'll be right over there.
抱歉  戈登
Sorry, Gordon.
我相信没有我们你也会做得很好的
I'm sure you'll do fine without us.
你们就是俩懦夫
You guys are a couple of cowards.
用户开始来了
The first users are showing up!
你好  欢迎  我是唐娜·克拉克
Hi, welcome. I'm Donna Clark.
你可以去热浴缸里享受食物和啤酒
You can help yourself to some food and beer's over in the hot tub.
-你是唐娜·克拉克  -对
- You're Donna Clark. - Yeah.
我想象中你很胖  特别胖
I pictured you as fat. Like, really fat.
谢谢啊
Thank you?
你好
Hi there.
你的服装呢
Hey, where's your costume?
我们不是说要玩角色扮演吗  间谍和哨兵
I thought we were going in character, spy and sentry.
我们是讨论过  但我不...
Uh, yeah, we talked about it, but I didn't--
不是吧你  这下我傻帽了
Seriously? Now I look weird.
那你来吗
Well, are you comin'?
我要去做点事  收个尾
I'm-- uh, yeah. I'm gonna do some work and finish up,
一会儿就出来
but I'll be out in a minute.
-好吧  -你看上去很不错
- Okay. - You look good.
谢谢
Thanks.
除了主机箱都是标准的
It's all standard except for the custom cabinets.
交换机连接到3090型服务器的系统网络接口
Connect the PBXs to the SNA inputs on the 3090, okay?
都在这里
It's all here,
但如有必要你可以把我的号码给他们
But you can give 'em my number if need be.
别这么快
Mm, back it up a little bit.
我需要你跟他讲讲我们所做的一切
I need you to walk him through what we've done.
我没这个时间
I don't have time for that.
给他这个就行  告诉他我跟你说的话
Just give him this, tell him what I told you,
他会明白的  好吗
He'll understand, all right?
好
Okay.
你没事吧
Everything all right?
嗯  我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
你呢  还有
How are you? How's, uh--?
莎拉  她很好
Sara. She's great.
好
Good.
我们结婚了
We got married.
什么
What?
没错  我们这几周
Yeah, we spent the past couple weeks
都在加州度蜜月
in California on our honeymoon.
真的吗
No kiddin'.
恭喜你们
Congratulations.
回头见  乔
See you later, Joe.
嗯
Yeah.
我们要搬去加州
Think we're movin' out there, to California,
所以我们要走了
so we'll be leaving.
也许一时半会儿见不到了
So this might be a good-bye for a while.
那么
Well, hey.
祝你好运
Best of luck.
你也是
Yeah, you, too.
我们登陆月球了吗  当然没有
Have we landed on the moon? Of course not.
你们看过《最后的星球斗士》吧
I mean, you guys have seen "Last Starfighter," right?
现在一切都能用特效做出来
They can do anything with special effects these days,
但谁最先拿到那种技术的呢
And who has access to that technology first?
是好莱坞吗
Hollywood?
不是吧
I don't think so.
詹姆斯  你好吗
James, how are ya?
那么这就是穆特尼了
Okay, so, this is Mutiny.
对  就是这里
Yeah, this is it.
来  我带你四处转转
Come on, let me show you around.
博迪
Hey, Bodie.
这是我儿子詹姆斯
This is my son James.
真奇怪啊
Weird.
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
博斯竟然有个儿子
Boz has a son.
走吧
Come on.
詹姆斯  我跟你说
You know, I tell you, James.
也许看不出来  但这些孩子都聪明绝顶
It may not look like much, but these kids are brilliant.
你不会相信的
You would not believe.
你在干吗呢  为什么不出去
What are you doing? Why aren't you outside?
我只是在给游戏收尾  马上就出去
Uh, I'm just finishing up the game. I'll be out in a minute.
游戏已经完成了  快点
The game is done. Come on.
这可是你的公司
This is your company.
看来以为能说服你别那么做真是太傻了
Well, I guess it was stupid to think I talked you out of it.
别这样  我在保护我们的作品
Oh, come on. I'm protecting our work.
你对我有一丁点尊重吗
Do you have any respect for me?
我十分尊重你
I respect the shit out of you.
你不尊重我的想法
You don't value my opinion--
-算了  -不  汤姆  怎么了
- Never mind. - No, Tom. What?
快说啊  这里人人都生我气
Come on, everyone is pissed at me in this house
但又没人肯说出来
and no one's saying anything.
快把我逼疯了  究竟怎么了
It's driving me crazy. What is it?
好吧  让我生气的是  我说想卖掉
Okay, it pisses me off that I told you that I wanted to sell,
-可后来乔告诉你不该卖  -我的天
- and then Joe tells you that you shouldn't... - Oh, god.
-而你听从了他的意见  -你想卖掉
- ...And that you listened to him. - You want to sell?
-汤姆  他们想毁了我们  -不是为了那个
- Tom, they were gonna ruin this company! - It's not about--
不是卖不卖的问题  而是关于你和我
No, it's not about the sale. It's about you and me.
好吧  你听好了  如果你想分手
Fine, you know what? Just break up with me
那就分手好了  我们也能...
if you're gonna break up with me and we can--
我不想和你分手  我只是...
I'm not gonna break up with you. I'm just--
我是生你的气  你懂吗
I'm just mad at you, okay?
我可以生你的气吧
And I can be mad at you, right?
-你什么意思  想辞职吗  -不  我不想辞职
- So, what, you wanna quit? - No, I don't want to quit.
我爱你  我为什么要辞职
I love you. Why would I quit?
你以前没和人有过不同意见吗
Have you ever had a disagreement before?
我们不过是在谈谈  是人都谈话
We're just talking. People talk.
人们还打架  还争论
They fight. They argue.
这是常有的事
It happens every single day.
你爱我
You love me?
什么  不  你这是乱说
What? N-no-- now you're putting words in my mouth.
不  你刚刚说了
No. You said those words.
就是这位  卡梅伦老板
Hey, there she is, the big boss, Cameron.
这是我儿子詹姆斯
This is my son James.
喂
Hello?
小宝贝  露营怎么样
Hey, hey, sweetie. How's camp?
是吗  你做了什么
Oh, yeah? What'd you make?
摇摆木马  你一个人做的吗
A rocking horse? All by yourself?
上色了吗
Did you paint it?
JDL定制电脑
紫色
Purple?
兔崽子
Son of a bitch.
抱歉  亲爱的  不是说你
No, sorry, sweetheart. Not you.
听起来很棒嘛  亲爱的
That all sounds great, sweetie.
爸爸得挂了  好吗
Look, dad's gotta go, okay?
你明天打给我好吗
Will you call me tomorrow?
好的  好的  我爱你
Okay. Okay, I love you.
是啊  戈登·克拉克的想法真是与众不同
Yeah, Gordon Clark's got a unique mind.
-是啊  这个想法不错  -是啊
- Clearly. This is pretty cool. - Yeah.
如果你要改成更传统的布局
Yeah, if you're gonna switch over to a more conventional setup,
那我最好还是再留几天
maybe it'd be best if I stuck around for a few days
帮你检查故障吧
to help troubleshoot with you.
你还有更重要的事要做
You got bigger fish to fry.
加州在召唤呢  对吧
California's calling, right?
对啊
Yeah.
你真的该找个硬件专家来
You should definitely bring on a hardware specialist.
扩容工作会需要这方面的丰富经验
The expansion's gonna require lots of expertise in that area.
后面的事就让我来操心吧
I got it from here. It's my problem to worry about.
谢谢你的帮助
Thanks for your help.
莱夫
Lev?
-莱夫  你来了  -大家好啊
- Lev, you made it! -  Hey, guys.
-悠悠球  -真逗
- Yo-yo! - That's funny.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
-我可不想错过  -我知道
- I wasn't about to miss this. - I know.
我想看看这些怪人本尊是什么样
Wanted to see what these freaks were like in person.
见到你真好
It's really good to see you.
莱夫  你看起来好虚弱
Lev! You look so fragile.
我想抱抱你  可是...
I want to hug you, but--
轻点就行  博迪
Just be careful, Bodie.
听说新游戏很棒
Heard the new game was pretty cool.
就想来看看
Decided to check it out.
是啊  我觉得你会喜欢的
Yeah, I think you'll dig it.
谢谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
-卡梅伦  -怎么了
- Cameron? - Yeah.
大家都到了
Hey, we're all here now.
我觉得该致辞了
I feel like it's a good time to say something.
-好  去吧  -不  不是我  是你
- Yeah, go ahead. - No, not me, you.
不  唐娜  我真不喜欢致辞
No, Donna, I really don't like to do that.
-快去  -好吧
- Go. - Okay.
大家好
Hello.
Hi, hi, everybody.
在场大多数人我都见过了
Uh, I've met a lot of you already,
为初次见面的各位自我介绍一下
but to those of you I haven't,
我是唐娜·克拉克
I'm Donna Clark.
感谢大家光临
Thank you all for coming.
现在我想为大家介绍
And now I would like to introduce to you
穆特尼的主脑
the mind behind Mutiny,
我们的领袖  卡梅伦·豪伊
our leader Cameron Howe!
-棒  卡梅伦  -豪伊  豪伊  豪伊
- All right, Cameron! - Howe! Howe! Howe!
大家好  我是卡梅伦
Hi, I'm cameron.
开场词不错
Nice start!
就是这样
There it is.
我们要宣布一件事
Oh, we have an announcement to make.
今天我们在为新游戏进行最后的润色
Uh, today we're putting the finishing touches on our latest game.
游戏的名字叫做《营救保卫战》
It's called "Extract & defend."
棒
Yeah!
今天来了多少玩家
How many gamers do we have here today?
这里
Yes!
我想大家会喜欢我们的游戏
Well, I think you guys are really gonna love what we've done, so...
走  去拿杯啤酒
Come on. Let's grab a beer.
好
All right.
跟你的出版商朋友说过了吗
Talk to your publisher friend?
珍妮特吗  说了
Jeanette? Yeah.
我们到了我要约她喝咖啡
I'm gonna meet with her for coffee once we're back out there.
你的最后一天如何  新人怎么样
How was your last day? How's the new guy?
他很棒  我很喜欢他
Uh, yeah, he's great. Like him a lot.
很年轻
Young.
没有我期望的硬件经验  不过...
Doesn't have the hardware experience I would've expected, but...
也不错了
seems nice enough.
-你讨厌他  -什么  不
- You hated him? - What? No.
一点儿也不
Not at all.
这里明显有股厌恶的能量
Well, there's a palpable hate energy here.
不知道  我说不清楚
Oh, I don't know. I can't put my finger on it.
让他做这份工作似乎不太合适
He seems like an odd choice for the job.
你会想念它的
You're gonna miss it.
还会有其他机会
Oh, there'll be other projects
比试图将石油公司带入未来
way more exciting than trying to take
刺激得多的工作
an oil company into the future.
当然  是啊
Of course, yeah.
过来
Hey, come here.
Come here.
你是自然之力
You're a force of nature.
你将世界打造成你想要的样子
All right? You make the world what you want it to be.
到了加州也是一样
It'll happen in California, too.
不如这样吧
H-how about this?
我们今晚离开现实世界
How about we step out of reality for the night,
来一次硬重启
a hard reboot?
我觉得等你到了外面
I think once you're outside,
就会意识到什么是真正重要的东西
you'll realize what's really important.
我怎么到外面去
How do I get on the outside?
我打扫柜子时发现了一些东西
Well, I found something when I was cleaning out the closet.
-那是什么  -摇头丸
- What is that? - MDMA.
我写调查报告时用的
From when I was doing the exposé.
我们今晚出去玩吧  我们去斯塔克俱乐部
Let's go out tonight. Let's go to the Starck Club.
好好向达拉斯告别
We can bid Dallas a fond farewell.
让他们知道他们会失去什么
Show them what they'll be missing.
-你还记得大学时那个莎拉吗  -记得
- You remember college Sara? - Yeah.
我一直跟不上她的节奏
I couldn't keep up with her.
那你最好加把劲了
Well, you'd better do your best.
你来了
Hey, you made it!
感谢上帝  有几个人你真该见见
Thank god! There's some people here you really have to meet.
有个人  在社区结识了女友
This one guy, he proposed to his girlfriend
已经向她求婚了
after they met on community.
-多棒啊  -非常棒  亲爱的
- How cool is that? - That's, uh-- that's great, honey.
看
Look.
-怎么了  怎么回事  -有人偷了我的点子
- What? What is this? - Someone stole my idea.
你的点子关键在你  在于戈登·克拉克
Oh, well, your idea is about you. It's about Gordon Clark.
专家打造的电脑
Computers handmade by an expert.
谁知道这些家伙是谁
Who knows who these guys are?
你看  价位一模一样
All right, look. The price point's the same.
连宣传口号都几乎一样
I mean, the slogan's nearly identical.
戈登  别这样  来喝点啤酒  好好享受派对
Gordon, come on. Let's get a beer. Let's enjoy the party.
我觉得是斯坦干的
I think it was Stan.
什么  就是那个斯坦吗
What, Stan, Stan?
我觉得他拉上了艾德和拉里
I think he got Ed and Larry involved.
我该去找他吗...
Should I go over there? I mean, should--
-不  -我应该说些什么吗
- No. - Should I say something?
不  我觉得算了吧
No, I don't think so.
我们可以...我们明天再仔细看看
Look, we can-- we should take a careful look at this tomorrow.
可能只是一个巧合
It's probably just a coincidence.
就算不是
Even if it's not,
克拉克电脑的地位也不会受到撼动
there's nothing they can do to hurt Clark Computers
因为他们没有最珍贵的资源  对吗
'cause they don't have the most valuable asset, right?
来嘛  我们好好玩玩
Come on, let's go hang out a little bit.
不
No.
我觉得我还是回家吧  我有点累了
I think I'd better go home. I'm feeling a little fried.
好吧
Oh, okay.
去吧  去睡一会儿吧
Yeah, go-- go get some sleep, then.
好
Okay.
唐娜  你看
Hey, Donna! Check this out!
谢了
Thanks.
-你是卡梅伦·豪伊吗  -是啊
- Cameron Howe? - Yeah.
不好意思  你还不认识我
Sorry, you don't know me.
我叫格雷琴
My name is Gretchen.
这是你的公司吧
This is your company, right?
是啊
Uh... Yeah.
是啊  没错
Yeah, it is.
我只是想说谢谢你
I just want to say thank you.
我们家一团糟
My family's kind of screwed up.
简直糟糕透顶
Well, really screwed up.
在我发现穆特尼之前  根本没法找人倾诉
I didn't have anyone to talk to about it until I found Mutiny.
那里有很多人
There are a bunch of people
也面临同样的问题  他们帮助了我
dealing with the same sort of stuff and they help me.
他们帮我意识到  我可以一走了之
They helped me realize that-- that I could walk away.
我没有什么毛病
that there wasn't anything wrong with me.
要是没有你  我根本做不到
And I couldn't have done that without you.
如果你觉得奇怪  那很抱歉
I'm sorry if that sounds weird.
不会
No.
谢谢
Thank you.
没事  不客气
No, it's not at all.
感觉好棒
This feels so good!
不是吧
Oh-ho, really?
跟上节奏哦
Try and keep up.
新娘怎么样了
Hey, how's the bride?
你们打算生孩子吗
You gonna pop out a couple of pups?
回头再说吧  有的是时间
Oh, we'll see. We got time.
你妈妈肯定会高兴的
It'd sure make your mom happy.
为这个原因要孩子太糟糕了
That's a terrible reason to have children.
是啊
Yes, indeed.
詹姆斯
Well, James...
-谢谢你能来  -当然的
- Thanks for coming. - Sure.
爸爸  我知道有个工作在招人
Listen, dad, I know about this job opening.
是个客户经理的位置
It's, uh, an account manager's position.
我知道你离开卡迪夫时是个副总裁
And I know you left Cardiff as a vp,
但这公司不错  我认识那些人
but it's a solid company. I know the people.
我可以替你美言一句
I could put in a good word.
可以让你离开这里
We can get you out of here.
-谢谢  詹姆斯  -嗯
- Thank you, James. - Yeah.
好了
Okay, all right.
-好吧  晚安  -晚安  儿子
- All right, good night. - All right, good night, son.
你一直在躲我
Hey, you've been avoiding me.
-没有啊  -就是有
- No, I haven't. - Yes, you have.
自从你说了"我爱你"之后
Ever since you said you love me.
嗯  好吧  我爱你
Yes, fine. I love you.
而且  要我说"我爱你"都算轻的了
In fact, I would say "I love you" is a dramatic understatement.
我觉得你方方面面都不可思议
I think you're incredible in pretty much every way.
如果这对你来说是个问题
If it's gonna be a problem for you,
那我也没办法  因为
then I don't know what to say, because...
事情就是如此  这是不会变的
it is what it is and it's not gonna change,
即使你像今天这一整天那样
even when you're being a total pain in the ass,
烦人透顶
like you have been this entire day.
好吧
Okay.
你就说出来吧
Just say the words, okay?
你如果不说  要别扭死了
This is gonna be so much weirder if you don't just say the words.
看着我
Look at me, look at me.
说出来吧
Say the words.
不行
No.
怎么了...说啊  说出来
What's... say the words. Just say them.
你坏死了
You're terrible.
我收回  我全部收回
I take it back. I take it all back.
天呐  戈登
Jesus, Gordon?
你干什么呢
What the hell are you doing here?
我知道你偷了我的点子
I know you stole my idea.
JGL电脑  有印象吗
JGL Computers. Sound familiar?
你让他们给我搞破坏
You had the guys sabotage me.
串行接口  还在上面写我的名字
The serial ports, putting my name on the back of it
好让克拉克电脑出丑
just to make Clark Computers look like a joke.
我根本不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
否则你为什么从加州回来
Why else would you come back from California?
你要用风投的钱
You gonna use some of that VC money
启动你的公司吗  你个混蛋
to get it started, you son of a bitch?
我回来是因为我受够了被一群25岁的毛头小子
I came back because I was tired of being laughed out of the room
哄笑赶走
by a bunch of 25-year-olds.
-我被淘汰了  -那这些都是什么
- I washed out. - Well, then, what the hell are these?
我总得挣钱  我在做维修
I gotta make ends meet. I'm doing repairs.
整天开车到处收集废旧机器
I'm driving around all day picking up these busted machines.
戈登  我能问问吗  你又嗑可卡因了吗
Gordon, can I ask? Are you doing coke again?
什么
What?
当然没有
No, of course not.
你为什么要那么想啊
Why would you even think that?
因为你大半夜闯进我车库
'cause you're in my garage in the middle of the night
指责我偷了你的点子
accusing me of stealing from you.
唐娜叫哥几个盯着你点
Donna told the guys to keep an eye on you,
而且他们说  你最近表现是不太正常
and according to them, you've been acting a little nuts.
-唐娜叫你做什么  -我不知道
- Donna told you what? - I don't know.
是他们说  这下我卷进
But the guys said... now I'm getting into the middle of something
-我不想掺和的事里了  -跟你说什么了
- that I don't want to get... - Told you what?
她说你如果表现怪怪的就告诉她
That... she said to tell her if you were acting strange
或者如果感觉你被工作累坏了什么的
Or, you know, like the job was taking a toll on you or something.
她是担心你
She was worried about you.
唐娜
Donna?
难以置信
Unbelievable.
你觉得她是想害我歇业吗
You think she's trying to shut me down?
天呐  又是这样
God, it's the same thing all over again.
不不  你误会了
No, no, no, you got it all wrong.
她只是担心你
She was looking out for you.
你叫警察来抓我
You called the cops on me?
斯坦  你干吗报警抓我
Stan, why would you call the cops on me?
我听到有人闯进我家啊
Because I heard someone breaking into my house.
斯坦  你怎么想的  你干吗这么做
Stan, what were you thinking? Why would you do that?
-干什么  -没事的
- Hey, what the hell? - It's okay.
-够了  -我只想跟我朋友谈谈
- That's it, that's it. - I just want to talk to my friend
问他他为什么要报警抓我
and ask him why he called the cops on me.
我只想谈谈
I just wanted to talk...
你好棒
You're amazing.
好棒
Amazing.
我觉得我有很多优点  很多优秀之处
I feel like there's a lot of goodness in me, a lot of greatness,
但却发挥不出来  无法展现给世界
but I can't get it out of me. I can't give it to the world.
我有想法  我不是个回声
I have ideas. I'm not an echo.
我能在脑袋里构想  却做不出来
I make things in my mind, but I can't get them into the world.
我过不了这一关  像个陷阱一样
I can't get past this. It's like a trap.
就好像世界不肯看到真正的我
Like the world won't see the... me... the real me.
不  我看到你了
Oh, no, I see you.
你是自然之力
You're a force of nature.
你会改变世界的
You're gonna change the world.
我有想法
I have ideas.
在线可以有大发展
Online could be more.
而不是只有程序员们
It could be more than just inside bullshit
才懂的天书
for anointed coder shitheads.
是可以走向全球的  可以在上面生活的
It could be universal. You could live your life there.
它能改变一切的  我保证
It would change everything, I promise you.
我们如今生活的世界到时候会像石器时代
The world we live in now is going to look like the stone age.
这些人  他们的东西
All these people with their things.
这个物质世界已死
The physical world is dead.
一条道路正在修建起来
A pathway is being built.
这条路通向纯粹信息的世界
A way out, into a world of pure information.
集体意识
A shared consciousness.
未来像一列货运列车一样
The future is bearing down on us
向我们压了过来  却没人看得到
like a freight train and nobody sees it.
要走了吗
Is this a good good-bye?
准备离开达拉斯了吗
You ready to get the hell outta Dallas?
我再道别一下
I just wanna say one last good-bye.
我一直告诉自己穆特尼的关键是游戏
I kept telling myself that Mutiny was games, we are about games.
我觉得  我知道今天我如果走出去
And I think... I knew that if I went outside today
看到你成就的一切
and saw what you'd done that
我就再也没法那么骗自己了
I wouldn't be able to tell myself that anymore.
结果我想对了
It turns out I was right.
我只是希望这里能做探索先锋
I just want this place to be about exploration.
抱歉我挡了你的路
I'm sorry that I stood in your way.
谢谢
Thank you.
我也想参与进来
I'd like to be a part of it.
你已经参与了啊  你建造了这里
You are a part of it. You built this place.
不  我是指
No, but I mean...
在游戏这边  我们一直在改进代码  对吧
So, on the game side, we're always pushing the code, right?
我们总想做到最好
We're trying to get the most out of it.
如果我们把这种精力拿到社区上去呢
But what if we applied that same pressure to community?
其功能会大大提升
I mean, the functionality of it could explode.
运行更快  主题间切换更自如
It could run faster, smoother between subjects
或者找到特定用户对话更方便
or finding certain users' conversations.
嗯  那些都对
Yeah, yeah, all of that,
另外  我们还可以做界面
and then also we could make the interface
做得更像游戏  但不是
more like a game's interface, except not.
这是一个需要探索的世界
But, you know, it was a world to navigate
不是一张清单  是一张地图
and not a list, but it was a map, you know?
这地方让你性奋吗
This place turns you on?
相当性奋
You have no idea.
天呐
Oh, my god.
我们得走了
Okay, we gotta go.
快点  穿上裤子
Come on. Pants...
我去看看怎么回事
I want to see what's going on.
不不  等等
No, no, no, wait.
他们看不见我们
They can't see us.
我爸爸如果知道了  我死定了
If my father hears about this, I'm gonna die.
你上车  我待会儿去找你
You go to the limo and I'll meet you there.
我...会小心的
I'm... I'll be stealthy.
还有什么比这更好
What's better than this?
好了
All right.
Okay.
我想下来恭喜大家干得好  各位
I just wanted to come down here to say job well done, guys.
这个任务并不轻松
It was a bitch of an assignment,
但你们做得很好
but you guys stepped up, seriously.
所以...
So...
敬西方网络
To WestNet!
西方网络
天呐  然后还可以
Oh, my god, and then you could,
在话题间游走
you know, walk from topic to topic.
嗯  比那更好的是
Yeah, and better than that,
还可以在那些地方找到其他用户
you could find other users at those places.
嗯  我觉得我们该写下来
Yes, okay, I feel like we have to write this down.
我们有没有...
Do we have something...
卡尔  把公告板擦干净好吗
Carl, could you clear off the bulletin board?
我们要写一下社区的结构
We need to create a layout for community.
打印张所有聊天室的清单  卡尔
I want a list printed of every room... Carl.
卡尔  你看什么呢
Carl, what are you looking at?
我也不知道我看什么呢
I... I don't know what I'm looking at.
我登的是穆特尼
I logged into Mutiny.
以管理员身份登录一下
Try to log on as an administrator.
-我被锁在外面了  -怎么回事
- Uh, I'm locked out. - What's wrong?
我不明白  穆特尼呢
I don't get it. Where's Mutiny?
我们被踢下网络了
We're kicked off the network.
被这个替掉了
Replaced by this.
穆特尼没了
There is no Mutiny.
不见了
It's gone.
计划有变  我要先去个地方
Change of plans. I'd like to make another stop.
电话线都汇集到西方集团的调制解调器组
The phone lines terminate in modem banks at WestGroup.
他们给调包了  用户连接服务器时
They switched them over, so now when you dial in,
虽然连的地址没变
the same number you've always dialed,
但却进的是西方网络而不是穆特尼
you get WestNet instead of Mutiny.
他们偷了我们所有的用户
They've stolen all our users.
他们还克隆了我们的界面
They even cloned our interface,
大部分人可能都没发现这不穆特尼
so most people don't even know they're not on Mutiny.
他们会以为是我们换了名字
They think we changed the name.
上社区论坛
Okay, get on the community forums
告诉他们这不是穆特尼
and tell them they're not on Mutiny.
他们全克隆走了吗
What, they cloned the whole thing?
是啊  所有东西  除了游戏
Yes, everything, except games.
嗯  因为他发现摇钱树其实是社区
Yeah, 'cause he realized community is where the money was.
叫他们下线
Just tell them to log off
等我们换网络
and wait for us to find another network.
等我们  天呐
Wait for us? Oh, christ.
何必花500万美元买我们
I mean, why pay $5 million for us
他们可以直接复制我们  偷我们所有的用户
when they can just duplicate us and steal all of our users?
喂  我是穆特尼的汤姆·兰顿
Hello, hi, hi. This is Tom Rendon from Mutiny.
有家公司抢了我们的网络
Another company's taken over our network and I just...
不  看着像我们  但其实不是  你得下线
No, it looks like us, but it's not us. You need to log off.
我们会尽快上线  再过一两周吧
We'll be up again in... A week or two?
-喂  该死  -喂
- Hello... damn it! - Hello?
他们不明白
They don't understand.
他们还在跟同样的用户交流
They're still communicating with all the same users.
他们的朋友现在都上西方网络了
All of their friends are on WestNet now.
不不  怎么能这样
No, no, this isn't happening!
卡梅伦呢
Where's Cameron?
出事了  我得跟她谈谈
Something's happened and I need to talk to her.
卡梅伦呢
Where... where's Cameron?
Where's Cameron?
我得跟她谈谈  出事了
I got... I need to talk to her. Something's wrong.
卡梅伦呢
Uh, where's... where's Cameron?
我直接跑过来了
I came straight here.
我完全不知情
I didn't know about this.
我不知道会这样
I didn't know that this was happening.
我完全不知道  维勒什么都没告诉我
I had no idea that... Wheeler shut me out and...
不  我...
No, I...
我要搬去加州了
I'm... I'm moving to California.
我几周前就交了辞呈
I... I gave my notice weeks ago.
我没理由做这种事  我是你这边的
There's no reason I would've done this. I'm on your side.
我不会这么做的
I wouldn't do this.
我保证  我不会的
I promise you, I wouldn't do this.
我不会这么做的
I wouldn't do this.
这根本没道理
It's... it doesn't make any sense.
有个人  杰西  是他干的
There's this guy, Jesse... he did this.
我不...我没有
I don't... I mean, I didn't...
该死
Damn it! Uh...
我都不在那儿工作了
I don't even work there.
我要去加州了
I'm going to California.
卡梅伦  你得听我的
Cameron, I need you to hear me.
你走吧
You need to leave.
不  你不懂
No, you don't understand.
走吧  乔
Now, Joe.
她为什么要这么做
Why would she be doing this?
你相信他吗
Do you believe him?
完全不信
Not for a second.
好吧  那我们怎么办
Okay, so what are we gonna do now?
卡梅伦  我们现在怎么办
Cameron, what are we gonna do now?